Quan Katie ILGWU Papers and Publications 6036/095
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Katie Quan ILGWU Papers and Publications
1974-1989
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Quan, Katie
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
6036/095
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Papers, publications, songbooks.
This is Katie Quan's collection of ILGWU Local 23-25 newsletters, pamphlets, and songbooks. Also included are Ms. Quan's papers regarding her education as a Union Local official.
9392991
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, August 24, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/059: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/059 P: ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs 5780/059 PUBS: ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications 5780/095: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095 G: ILGWU Local 23-25 graphics 6000/024: UNITE Local 23-25 Records 6000/024 Av: UNITE Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials 6000/024 MB: UNITE Local 23-25 Memorabilia 6000/024 P: UNITE Local 23-25 Photographs 6000/024 PUBS: UNITE Local 23-25 Publications 6000/050: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Files 6000/050 AV: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials 6000/050 MB: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Memorabilia 6000/050 P: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Photographs 6000/050 PUBS: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Publications 6200/005: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Files 6200/005 MB: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Memorabilia 6200/005 P: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Photographs 6036/095 MB: Katie Quan ILGWU Memorabilia
Quan, Katie; International Ladies Garment Workers Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.)
9392991
- ILG: Contracts (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Booklets
- 1976 Contracts (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1979 Contract (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1982 Contracts (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1988 Contract Clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
- IGL: '82: Union Summaries, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Issue of "Justice" and the Local 23-25
- IGL: '82: Strike Memos, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- IGL: '82: Terms of Settlement, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- IGL: '82:Union Propaganda, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- IGL: '82: Letters to Members, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- IGL: '82: Contract Demands, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- EMPL: OGMA (Box 1, Folder 12)
- EMPL: CGMA (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ILG: WrkrEd: Administration (Box 1, Folder 14)
- EMPL: GBSUA (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Holiday Pay (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Issues: Imports (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Misc.: 4,400 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ILG: Health (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Booklet
- Anti-Homework (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ILG: Anti-Imports Campaign (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ILG: Political Education (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 1984 H W Change (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Shop Representatives' Notebook (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Informational Folder; booklet
- ILG: Letters Re: Union Elections (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ILG: Letters Re: Benefits (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ILG: Letters Re: Polit. Camp (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ILG: WrkrEd: Constitution Structure of ILGWU (Box 2, Folder 4)
- ILG: Letters Re: Misc. Correspon. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ILG: Letters Re: Leadership (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ILG: Letters Re: Shop Rep. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ILG: Letters Re: Labor Laws (Box 2, Folder 8)
- ILG: WkrEd: Shop Rep. Manuals (Box 2, Folder 9)
- ILG: WkrEd: Role of Shop Rep. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- ILG: WkrEd: Grievance Procedure (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ILG: WkrEd: Health Safety (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ILG: WkrEd: Immigration Project (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ILG: WkrEd: Contract Provisions (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ILG: WkrEd: Media Outreach (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Misc.: Men T. Wu Cheng (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Misc.: Shiu Lun Lee (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Misc.: Bowery Theft (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Misc.: Housing Suit (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Misc.: Ben Fee (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Misc.: Gang Hing (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Misc.: Local 105 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- ILG: Justice 1989 Chinese (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 1976 Garment Contracts (Box 2, Folder 24)
- News: Union Elections (Box 2, Folder 25)
- News: State of Union (Box 2, Folder 26)
- News: Chinese in Garment (Box 2, Folder 27)
- News: Sweatshops (Box 2, Folder 28)
- News: ILG Ads (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Chinese News Clippings, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Misc.: Mob Influence (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Chinatown Press (Folder 1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Chinatown Press (Folder 2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Chinatown Press (Folder 3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Press Translations (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Press Releases (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Chinatown Press (Box 3, Folder 3)
- ILGWU (Box 3, Folder 4)
- ILGWU Songs (Box 3, Folder 5)
- ILG Chorus: Union Songs (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Worker Education: English Classes (Box 3, Folder 7)
- English Classes: Garment Workers Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Local 23-25 News (Box 3, Folder 9)
- ILG: 23-25 News 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- ILG: 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- ILG: 23-25 News (Misc.), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- AAFEE in Garment (Box 4, Folder 15)
- ILGWU Convention, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Informational Folder
- ILGWU On the Move, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Union Label (Box 4, Folder 18)
- ILGWU Organizing (Box 4, Folder 19)
- ILGWU Organization Structure (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Katie Quan (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Folder of information
- ILGWU Information (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Katie Quan (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Garment Industry (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Garment Industry (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Garment Industry (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Garment Industry (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Garment News Clippings from ICQ (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Garment News Clippings from ICQ (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sweatshop - Garment Industry (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Garment Industry Clippings (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Parshan Sportswear (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Shop Safety (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Garment Raids (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Chinese News Clippings (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Chinese News Clippings (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Local 81-22-1 Letter to Members (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Letters to Members (Box 6, Folder 11)
- ILG Memo for Staff (Box 6, Folder 12)